# Josh Woodcock <Front-End Engineer />

832-247-8742 // josh@j0w0.com // github.com/j0w00 // www.j0w0.com // www.linkedin.com/in/jrwoodcock

**Front-End Software Engineer** experienced in building reliable, manageable, and scalable websites and web applications. I develop quality products by utilizing appropriate technologies and applying best practices for data organization and code optimization.

Skills/Technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Gatsby, Node, Google Firebase, MongoDB, Express, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Cloud-based Deployment Services (AWS, Heroku, Netlify), Styled Components, Bootstrap, jQuery, PHP, Git, Creating/consuming RESTful APIs (Google, Stripe, Twilio), Wordpress, WooCommerce.

**Demos:** React demos include Celebrity Name Game and Event Manager. Tic-Tac-Toe (Robots vs. Babies), Simon, and Rock, Paper, Scissors are developed with vanilla Javascript. Code and more information is available on my GitHub.

#### **Experience**

## **Front-End Software Engineer**

Music Audience Exchange (MAX) | January 2021-Present | Austin, Texas (Remote)

- Develops front end of brand and artist livestream web apps that provide fans with the ultimate digital music experience. Features include event registration and voting, real-time chat, tips/donations via Stripe, and livestream video feed.
- Simplified development process for quicker turnaround by creating standardized templates for content and layout.
- Tech stack used includes React, Styled Components, Google Firebase, HTML, CSS, Javascript.

## Front-End/UX Developer

Remedy | January 2019-July 2020 | Austin, Texas

- Streamlined urgent care web app that saw an increase in appointments by over 1000% and helped win two stages of VC funding for the start-up. By leveraging open-source web technologies, e-commerce, and custom form flows, the app was easily managed, scaled, and monitored.
- Developed admin utilities to help service coordinators better assist patients during the scheduling process.
- Tech stack used includes PHP, MySQL, Wordpress, HTML, CSS, Javascript, Twilio, WooCommerce.

### MIS Web Developer

Ford Audio-Video | January 2017-January 2019 | Austin, Texas

- Architected/developed Wordpress theme and admin plugins allowing for easier management and sharing of content.
- Developed and maintained full-stack web apps in PHP and MySQL for marketing events that included customer/ exhibitor registration, check in and attendance, lead tracking, and online payments via Stripe.
- Tech stack used includes PHP, MySQL, Wordpress, HTML, CSS, jQuery, Twilio, Stripe.

### **Digital Media Marketing Coordinator**

Ford Audio-Video | July 2014-January 2017 | Austin, Texas

Maintained earlier versions of the company's website, event landing pages, and staff Intranet.

#### **Education**

#### **Texas State University**

Bachelor of Fine Arts, Communication Design | San Marcos, Texas | May 2014

#### **General Assembly**

Software Engineering Immersive | Austin, Texas | October 2020